<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Introduction to the Command Line</title>
        <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/</link>
        <description>Introduction to the Command Line</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Redirection</title>
    <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/06redirects/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/06redirects/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Using outputs as inputs This page will cover some more advanced ways of using the command line, in particular how to link different commands together. Firstly we will cover a concept called &ldquo;redirection&rdquo;. Move into the folder example_files. We can see, for example, the first three lines of plants.txt with the command
head -3 plants.txt But what if, instead of printing the output to the terminal, we wanted to put it into a file?]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Searching</title>
    <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/05searching/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/05searching/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Searching for files We can use the program find as our search command, but it has some strange syntax&hellip; if you are a little confused, you are not alone! The syntax is
 find [where to look] [what type of file] [&quot;the match you are looking for, in quotes&quot;]  Let&rsquo;s go back to your folder command_line_files, and try each of these commands.
find . -iname &#34;data1&#34; find . -iname &#34;data*&#34; find .]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Editing files</title>
    <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/04editing_files/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/04editing_files/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Text editors We can create and modify files on the command line using text editors. These are like very minimal word-processors, with no formatting options, but with many powerful ways of editing that are not available in word-processors. There are lots of different command line editors, which range from user-friendly (but less powerful), to more difficult (but powerful and fast, once learned).
Info  Here are some common editors you might come across, or choose to learn:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Viewing the contents of files</title>
    <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/03viewing_files/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/03viewing_files/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Viewing files There are two main ways of viewing the contents of files on the command line: &ldquo;printing&rdquo; the output to the terminal window, and viewing file contents with a &ldquo;pager&rdquo;.
cat Let&rsquo;s look at outputting first with a command called cat. Sadly, this has nothing to do with small furry felines. Move into the folder called example_files, and run this command
cat meaning_of_life.txt which means &ldquo;output the contents of of the file &ldquo;meaning_of_life.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Working with files</title>
    <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/02manipulation/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/02manipulation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Learn more  We give some warnings on this page, but don&rsquo;t be intimidated! Mistakes are only human, and you won&rsquo;t be able to damage your computer through any of these commands.
To improve your skills in backing up, version control, and minimising risk in computing, look for our courses on Best Practices in Software Engineering.
   From this point forward, we will be working with the course materials (this is the same file as linked on the home page of this course).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>File system navigation</title>
    <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/01navigation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/01navigation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Where am I? Let&rsquo;s run our first command:
pwd With pwd we are asking &ldquo;print my current working directory / where am I?&rdquo; You will then get some output to the terminal window, something like
/home/at9362 This is your current location, here shown as an &ldquo;absolute path&rdquo; - the full description for what folder you are in. The sign ~ is an abbreviation for &ldquo;your home folder&rdquo;.
Tip  There are five abbreviations for locations that you might come across]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Welcome to the command line!</title>
    <link>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/00intro/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://altanner.github.io/intro-to-command-line-deploy/posts/00intro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The prompt When you open a terminal, you will be provided with a prompt. This tells you where you are, and provides a line where you will type your commands. Here is what a typical prompt looks like:
[at9362@dc2-d0:~] $ Your prompt will look different, but here is what it means
[ your-name @ computer-name : the-current-folder ] $ Here, the computer name (also known as the &ldquo;hostname&rdquo;) is dc2-d0, but yours might be more friendly, like Megans_iMac or ubuntu, for example.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
